<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>R on A Hugo website</title>
    <link>/categories/r/</link>
    <description>Recent content in R on A Hugo website</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 18 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/categories/r/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Build a Spotify Playlist Recommendation Model With R</title>
      <link>/2020/05/18/build-a-spotify-playlist-recommendation-model-with-r/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2020/05/18/build-a-spotify-playlist-recommendation-model-with-r/</guid>
      <description>Author: Ed OrlandoRecognition &amp;amp; CreditThis article and its contents were heavily influenced by Matt Dancho’s Learning Labs: Session #11. For more about Learning Labs Pro, please click here.

Problem StatementMany companies and products you interact with every day include some type of Recommendation system. For example, the Netflix app recommends movies based on your history and what is trending.
Amazon lists recommended items based on your product purchase history or what you currently have in your shopping cart.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Loading Multiple Files from Various Folders in R</title>
      <link>/2020/05/14/loading-multiple-files-from-various-folders-in-r/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2020/05/14/loading-multiple-files-from-various-folders-in-r/</guid>
      <description>Author: Ed OrlandoProblem StatementThis tutorial shows you how to load multiple files from multiple folders using R. As a bonus, this article will also show you how to add the folder and file names to the tibble.
Load LibrariesTidyverse and readxl are the only libraries required for this tutorial.
library(tidyverse)library(readxl)
Data DescriptionIn this example, Spotify playlist data was downloaded using Exportify.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Gratitude and Motivation</title>
      <link>/2020/05/10/gratitude-and-motivation/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2020/05/10/gratitude-and-motivation/</guid>
      <description>Author: Ed OrlandoFirst, I want to give a shout out to the team at White Lodging. Our team leader Adam Hutsler and BI Manager Max Thomas are always coming up with creative ways to solve complex problems and create business value using Tableau and R.
I was also inspired to create this data science blog based on the work performed by Matt Dancho. His online learning platform Business Science University (BSU) walks you through how professional data scientists set up, build, and deploy bleeding edge machine learning models using R.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What Separates the Top PGA Tour Players from the Rest of the Field</title>
      <link>/2019/02/11/what-separates-the-top-pga-tour-players-from-the-rest-of-the-field/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2019/02/11/what-separates-the-top-pga-tour-players-from-the-rest-of-the-field/</guid>
      <description>Author: Ed OrlandoThis article identifies what separates the top PGA Tour players from the rest of the competition using H2O and LIME.
The article and visualization were produced using Tableau Public and the predictions and explainable machine learning techniques were performed in R.
Click here for the full article.
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>