<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on A Hugo website</title>
    <link>/post/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on A Hugo website</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 18 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Spotify Recommendation Model With R</title>
      <link>/2020/05/18/spotify-recommendation-model-with-r/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2020/05/18/spotify-recommendation-model-with-r/</guid>
      <description>Author: Ed OrlandoProblem StatementThis tutorial shows you how to create a Spotify Recommendation Algorithm using the recommenderlab() and arules() packages.
Load LibrariesTo get started, first load the libbraries listed below.
# Core &amp;amp; Vizlibrary(tidyverse)library(tidyquant)library(plotly)# Modelinglibrary(recommenderlab)library(arules)library(arulesViz)Load DataData was previously downloaded and organized. You may view the data here
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Loading Multiple Files from Various Folders in R</title>
      <link>/2020/05/14/loading-multiple-files-from-various-folders-in-r/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2020/05/14/loading-multiple-files-from-various-folders-in-r/</guid>
      <description>Author: Ed OrlandoProblem StatementThis tutorial shows you how to load multiple files from multiple folders using R. As a bonus, this article will also show you how to add the folder and file names to the tibble.
Load LibrariesTidyverse and readxl are the only libraries required for this tutorial.
library(tidyverse)library(readxl)
Data DescriptionIn this example, Spotify playlist data was downloaded using Exportify.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My First Post: Gratitude and Motivation</title>
      <link>/2020/05/10/my-first-post-gratitude-and-motivation/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2020/05/10/my-first-post-gratitude-and-motivation/</guid>
      <description>Author: Ed OrlandoFirst, I want to give a shout out to the team at White Lodging. Our team leader Adam Hutsler and BI Manager Max Thomas are always coming up with creative ways to solve complex problems and create business value using Tableau and R.
I was also inspired to create this data science blog based on the work performed by Matt Dancho. His online learning platform Business Science University (BSU) walks you through how professional data scientists set up, build, and deploy bleeding edge machine learning models using R.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>